beingtheparent.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy | Being The Parent

#### PRIVACY POLICY

We use Ezoic to provide personalization and analytic services on this website, as such Ezoic's privacy policy is in effect and can be reviewed [here](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/beingtheparent.com).  

**Mykids Ventures Private Limited** (“Company/Us/We/Our”) is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring you have a positive experience on Our website, [www.beingtheparent.com](http://www.beingtheparent.com/) (“Website/ Site”). This policy (“Policy”) outlines Our personal information handling practices for both online and offline data. If you give us personal information, We will treat it according to this Policy. By clicking “Sign Up” while registering on Our Website you (‘User/ You/ Your’) agree to be bound to the terms of this Policy and Terms of Services.

**Acknowledgment and Acceptance of Privacy Policy**

We encourage You to read this Policy to ensure You understand Our Policy practices.

We adhere to the following principles to protect Your privacy:

We do not rent or sell Your personally identifiable information to third parties for any purposes.

Any personally identifiable information that You provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.

If We undertake any modifications to this policy, We will highlight the same on Our homepage and for any material change made, We also aim to send You an email notification of the same. To continue using the Site and the services post such changes or modifications You will be required to accept this Policy once again by clicking on ‘Accept/Agree’ tab.

  * **Personal Information collected:   **

To provide the services We collect some information from You.

We collect Your personal information in the following ways when You register to use the Site.

  * **Registration:   **

As a web based platform, We enable You to register for the services and create an account on Our Website. Your settings and control is completely monitored by You and We will only abide by Your settings.

On registration You are automatically eligible for all promotional offers and newsletters published by Us and our partners, We will provide You the ability to unsubscribe to the above if You choose so. You may be contacted by us or our partners for promotional activities. Your personal information will be used as per this Policy.

  * **Your Content:**

You may upload Your own content on Website.  This content is exclusively owned by You but licensed to Us for use as per this Policy and Terms of Service. In order to use Our Services, You are required to login through Your account, through which We will be able to identify, with the settings that You permit, of the basic profile information and all such information which is in public domain as per Your settings.

  * **  Log files, IP addresses and information about Your computer/mobile phone:**

As per the communications standards on the Internet, when You visit Our Website, We automatically receive the URL of the site from which You came and the Website to which You are going when You leave Website. We also receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of Your computer (or the proxy server You use to access the World Wide Web), Your computer operating system and type of web browser You are using, email patterns, as well as the name of Your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help Us improve the services and for internal business development. The linkage between Your IP address and Your personally identifiable information is not shared with third-parties without Your permission or except when required by law.

  * **Cookies and Web Beacons**

Like most websites, We use cookies and web log files to track Site usage. We use cookies to improve the quality of Our service by storing Your preferences and tracking Your usage trends. In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing services to You, We may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on Your browser. We do not store personally identifiable information in the cookies if You are a non-registered User. Any information that is stored is in an encrypted manner. Information if stored is purely for ease in accessing the services.

  * **Processing information about You and modification of such information**

All the information You provide to Us, including sensitive personal information, is voluntary. You have the right to withdraw Your consent at any time by duly modifying Your privacy and account settings. Please note that Your withdrawal of consent will not be retroactive.

You can access, modify, correct and eliminate the data about You which has been collected pursuant to Your decision to become a User. If You update any of Your information, We may keep a copy of the information which You originally provided to Us in Our archives for the purposes as documented herein. We take Your rights seriously and encourage You to use them if You deem this to be appropriate. You may exercise these rights by emailing us at support@beingtheparent.com

  * **External links.    **

This Policy applies to Site and services that are owned and operated by Us. We do not exercise control over the websites displayed as search results or links from within Our services or when You are sharing Your information on other websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on Your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from You, for which We are not responsible or liable. We encourage You to read the privacy policies of such website.

  * **Uses of Personal Information:**

We will not share Your personally identifiable information with other parties except as provided herein. Other information that does not personally identify You as an individual, is collected by Us from You (such as, patterns of utilization described above) and is exclusively owned by Us. This information can be utilized by Us in such manner as We, in Our sole discretion, deem appropriate. All the personally identifiable information is exclusively owned by You and You shall be responsible for such information, however by accepting Our Terms of Service and Policy You, agree to give a royalty free, worldwide, perpetual license to Us to use such information for promotional and distribution purpose.

  * **Sharing Your information with third party service provider:**

We may share  your information with any of Our third party service providers or merchants or partners. Any add-on services that we provide does not capture Your personal information and is done purely anonymously. Your usage trends will be used for internal business development purposes and to better the service provided to You.

  * **Communication and Update**

We will communicate with You through email and notices posted on Our Website. You can change Your e-mail and contact preferences at any time by logging into Your “Account” and change the account settings.

  * **Legal Disclaimer**

It is possible that We may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as responses to civil or criminal subpoenas, or other requests by law enforcement personnel. We will disclose such information wherein We have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, subpoena, or other legal process or request to Us brought in any country throughout the world, or to exercise Our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

  * **Disclosures to others**

We may also disclose Your personal and other information You provide, to another third party as part of reorganization or a sale of the assets of Company or division of Company. Any third party to which We transfer or sell Our assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that You provide to Us.

  * **Other uses:**

  * Providing Our Services to You, including the display of customized content and advertising;Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve Our services;Ensuring the technical functioning of Our network; andDeveloping new services.

  * **Disclosure of non-personally identifiable information:**

We may disclose or share non-personally identifiable information with partners, affiliates and advertisers. For example, We may share aggregated demographic information (which does not include any personally identifiable information) with third party advertisers and other parties as provided below:

We may use third party advertising companies to serve ads when You visit Our Website. These companies may use such information about Your visits to Our Site and other websites in order to provide, through the use of network tags, advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to You.  We may track and analyze Site usage and other statistical information to administer Our Site and constantly improve its quality. We may also publish this information for promotional purposes or as a representative audience for advertisers.

  * **Your choice in managing Your information**

  * **Closing Your account**

When You choose to close Your account on Our Website, We will remove Your name and other personally identifiable information from Our database. We may retain certain data contributed by You if We believe it may be necessary for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. You can close Your account by deactivating Your profile from the Site’s settings.

We encourage You to promptly update Your personally identifiable information if it changes. You may ask to have the information on Your account deleted or removed; however, because We keep track of past transactions, You cannot delete information associated with past transactions on the Website. In addition, it may be impossible for Us to completely delete all of Your information because We periodically backup information.

  * **Retrieval of information**

We internally have a process on information security and Your information being accessed only by those who are authorised. In situations where You accidentally delete Your information and would like to retrieve, then this core team may access the stored database and recover the same. Please be aware that this team may have to go through Your personal information in order to restore the information sought by You.

  * **Other Administrative activities**

As a condition to using the services, We will send You administrative and promotional emails. We will send You information regarding Your account activity as well as updates about Our service. If You do not want to receive promotional emails from Us, You may elect to opt-out of receiving by hitting the “unsubscribe” button at the bottom of any of Our e-mails.

  * **Information Security**

We take security seriously and take numerous precautions to protect the security of personally identifiable information. You can access Your personally identifiable information on Our Website by entering Your log-in credentials. This password is encrypted. We recommend that You do not share Your password with anyone. In addition, Your Personally Identifiable Information resides on a secure server that only selected personnel and contractors have access to.

Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while We employ commercially reasonable security measures to protect data and seek to partner with companies which do the same, We cannot guarantee the security of any information transmitted to or from the Site, and are not responsible for the actions of any third parties that may receive any such information

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of Our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where We store personal data.

  * **Users Obligations**

  * You must, at all times, respect the terms and conditions of the then-current Policy and the Terms of Service. This includes respecting all intellectual property rights which may belong to third parties.You must not create or otherwise disseminate any information which may be deemed to be injurious, violent, offensive, racist or xenophobic or which may otherwise violate the purpose and spirit of Company and its community of Users.You must not provide information to Us and /or other Users which you believe might be injurious or detrimental to Your person, professional or social status.

Any violation of these guidelines may lead to the restriction, suspension or termination of Your account by Us, as We take these principles seriously and consider them to be the basis on which Our Users adhere to Our Site and the services which We offer

  * **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this Policy with notice through email or otherwise. We will also notify a summary of changes on the Site homepage. Unless stated otherwise, Our current Policy applies to all information that We have about You and Your account.

  * **Contact details.**

If You have any questions about this Policy, please feel free to contact Us through Our Site
